Lucas Brown

RIGGING/TECHNICAL ARTIST

www.ImLucasBrown.com | (747)-221-4849 | <u>ImLucasBrown@gmail.com</u> vimeo.com/319548283

SUMMARY

Rigging/Technical artist with experience developing rigs, pipeline tools, and motion capture workflows for games and animation. Knowledgeable in various rigging techniques, animation, pipeline structures, yielding reliable and repeatable results. Motivated and excited to work with animators and programmers to bring characters to life.

Married | US Citzen

EXPERIENCE

PIPELINE TD - SUNRISE PRODUCTIONS (CONTRACT)

2019-

- > Full stack Python developer
 - Custom rigging application with node based code composition
- ➤ Integrating Pixar USD into existing Pipeline

RIGGING/TECHNICAL ARTIST - PRETTY SIMPLE GAMES

2017-2019

- > Character, vehicle, and prop rigs for mobile game (mGear/custom tools)
- > Developing motion capture workflows/tools (Xsens/Ikinema)
- > Animation tools (FBX exporter, pickers, and various ease of life tools)

TECHNICAL ARTIST - SVAD PRODUCTIONS (CONTRACT)

2017-2017

- > Rigged creatures for a VR proof of concept.
- > Expanded existing Python and MEL codebase for an in house geometry caching plugin.
- > Refactored legacy code to support newer versions of Maya.

MEDIA PRODUCTION SPECIALIST - SOUTHERN ADVENTIST UNIVERSITY

2013-2016

- Video editing and CG scene creation for short educational videos.
- Project management, pre-production, production, post-production for promotional and educational videos.

SKILLS

RIGGER | TECHNICAL ARTIST

- > Rigging
- > PyMel, cmds, OpenMaya, Qt
- Animation Pipeline
- Mocap Retargetting

SOFTWARE / PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

- ➤ Maya
- Pvthon
- ➤ gitHub

EDUCATION

B.S. Effects Animation *Collegedale, TN USA.*

2013 - 2017